ROBERT M. PUCCI

FULL CONTACT INFORMATION AVAILABLE ON REQUEST • ROB@Nerdcentric.com

QUALIFICATIONS SUMMARY

Lead Support Analyst with a proven record of enhancing technical support procedures, automating routine tasks, providing tailored software solutions, and surpassing all customer service level objectives. Comprehensive fifteen-year history with leading technologies, including multidisciplinary experience in:

- Windows 2003 and 2008 Server Administration
- Windows XP, Vista, 7 Desktop Support
- VMware ESX and ESXi Server Administration
- Windows Server Update Services

- Cisco and 3Com Network Administration
- ShoreTel VOIP Support
- Syntellect Call Center Administration and Scripting
- SharePoint 2010

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Senior Technical Analyst - Digi International, Davis, CA

November 2005-Present

Lead Windows Systems Administrator responsible for implementing and maintaining Windows 2008 servers and Windows 7 workstations in an Active Directory domain. Manage VMware ESX servers with SAN attached storage hosting Windows and Linux virtual machines. Responsible for administration of ShoreTel VOIP and Syntellect call center systems.

- Install, manage, and maintain HP DL 320, DL 360, and DL 380 based server infrastructure.
- Technical leader for Foresight business intelligence team. Configured SQL Server Integration Services to import data from three external data sources and designed scripts to replicate data to remote file stores.
- Selected and implemented Orion Network Performance Monitor to quickly detect, diagnose, and resolve systems performance issues and outages.
- Designed and programmed the Windows automation tool Script Zombie, www.ScriptZombie.com, which automated companywide software installations, configuration verification, and other routine desktop and server support tasks.
- Lead successful platform upgrade from SharePoint 2007 to SharePoint 2010.

Test Engineer II—Sprint, Rancho Cordova, CA

February 2004-October 2005

Lead maintenance technician on Sprint's National ACD platform. Researched, isolated, and resolved issues relating to the EADS Pointspan ACD and ETalk quality monitoring systems used in 46 Sprint call centers. Maintained, tested, and implemented Windows 2000 and 2003 servers. Provided end-user support for Windows XP and 2000 desktops.

- Maximized team productivity by designing Visual Basic and Procomm scripting solutions that automated daily maintenance, troubleshooting, and installation tasks.
- Designed and implemented a 2.8 terabyte Storage Area Network (SAN), yielding a 60 percent savings over budgeted amount.

Client Support Analyst IV—Sprint, Rancho Cordova, CA

June 2002-January 2004

Provided first through third tier support for Aspect and Intecom ACD systems used in 46 Sprint call centers, supporting 7,700 customer service agents. Troubleshot and resolved circuit outages at DS0 to DS3 levels. Completed engineering requests to configure and install ACD hardware.

- Developed an Intecom log analyzer to decode switch messages providing real-time alarm assessment, facility conversion, search, and filter capabilities decreasing root cause analysis times by 75 to 80 percent.
- Designed and implemented Access and Visual Basic solutions to track and maintain 7,700 roaming agent accounts replacing an antiquated Excel based system.

Senior Systems Technician—Sprint, Rancho Cordova, CA

April 1997-May 2002

Administered and supported an NT domain consisting of 720 workstations, spanning two Sprint customer service call centers. Interfaced with staff and vendor organizations to solve system related problems. Isolated and resolved local area and wide area network problems utilizing network sniffers, cable testers and common NT resources.

Weather Forecaster (1W071A)—United States Air Force, Multiple Locations

June 1987-March 1997

EDUCATION AND CERTIFICATIONS

Microsoft SQL Server Administration (MS 2779) Bachelor of Science, Information Technology (Summa Cum Laude) University of Phoenix, Sacramento, CA 2007

2003